H-He beat him...
!قد هزمه
H-He beat Captain Kuro!
!هـ-هزم القبطان كورو
Even the Marines were no match for Kuro of a Thousand Plans!
!الرجل الذي لم تستطع حتّى البحرية مضاهاته، كورو ذو المئة حيلة
But he really beat him!
!هزمه حقًّا
Just who are you?!
!من تكون؟
Monkey D. Luffy.
.مونكي دي لوفي
I'd never lose to a pirate who ditches his name and runs from the sea.
يستحيل أن أخسر ضد قرصان تخلّى عن اسمه وهرب من البحر
The only time a pirate should abandon his name is when he dies!
لا يتيعن على القرصان التخلي عن اسمه إلّا حال وفاته
Luffy?! Nope, doesn't ring a bell...
لوفي؟ لم أسمع به من قبل فعلًا
Remember my name for the rest of your lives!
تذكروا اسمي طالما حييتم
I'm the man who's gonna be King of the Pirates!
!فأنا الرجل الذي سيصير ملك القراصنة
This guy's...
...إنّه
Take him and go!
خذوه وغادروا
Never come back!
!لا تعودوا إلى هنا أبدًا
Run!
!اهربوا
You did good.
...أحسنت
Weigh anchor! Hurry!
!ارفعوا المرساة، بسرعة
I guess even you would collapse after all you've been through...
...حتّى أنت ستنهار بعد تلقيك لكل تلك الضربات
So...
،أخبرني
what were you mad about earlier?
ممّ كنت غاضبًا قبل قليل؟
I hate them.
.أنا أكرههم
They're wrong.
،إنّهم مخطئون
That's not how crewmates are supposed to act.
فلا ينبغي للرفاق التصرف هكذا
What're you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
It's in their nature.
،هذا واضح
Pirates aren't exactly the merry bunch you make them out to be.
القراصنة ليسوا صالحين كما تظنّهم
I want some meat.
أريد أكل لحمًا
You're unbelievable!
...إنّك
Can you keep everything that's happened here a secret?
هل يمكنكم أن تبقوا كلّ ما حدث هنا سرًّا؟
What?! Keep it a secret?!
ماذا؟ سر؟
Why would we do that?!
لمَ قد نفعل هذا؟
Yeah! After we just fought for the sake of the village!
صحيح، قاتلنا من أجل القرية
I bet it'll change how everyone thinks of you!
سيغيّر الجميع رأيهم بك أيضًا
You'll be the village hero!
!ستصبح بطل القرية
– Yeah!
!صحيح
Usopp, you need to clear up this misunderstanding.
...أوسوب-سان... عليك أن توضّح سوء فهم الجميع
What misunderstanding?
هذا ليس سوء فهم، فقد نادوني بالمُبالغ كالعادة فحسب
Why go and scare everyone when it's been settled?
لا داعي لإثارة رعب الجميع بشيء قد انتهى سلفًا
This was a one-time thing.
،بغضّ النظر عن أحداث هذه المرة
No pirate's going out of their way to attack a remote village like this one again.
فلن يهاجم قراصنة قرية معزولة كهذه
I'm just going to pretend that nothing ever happened.
سأدّعي أنّه لم يحدث شيء
It was all a lie.
كان كلّه كذبة
But of course, I can't force you.
...لن أرغمكم، ولكن
No, we can do it!
لا، أستطيع فعلها
If it's for the good of the village!
إن كان ذلك من صالح القرية
I agree!
أنا أيضًا
Me too! I'll never say a word, ever!
أنا أيضًا، سأصمت إلى الأبد
Kaya...
...كايا
Will that be hard for you?
أسيكون الأمر صعبًا عليك؟
No.
.كلّا
Where could Usopp be this morning?
أتساءل ماذا حدث لأوسوب-كن؟
It just doesn't feel right... I can't get motivated.
لا أعلم ما بي اليوم
Mommy...
...ماما
Is Mr. Liar not coming today?
ألن يأتي الأخ الكذّاب اليوم؟
That lying runt...
...ذلك الطفل المُبالغ الوغد
Why is he so late?!
أين هو اليوم؟
You think maybe I was a bit too harsh yesterday?
أقسينا عليه كثيرًا الأمس؟
I'm sure he'll be back to his old tricks tomorrow!
...سيعود لعادته بحلول الغد
Just watch.
حتمًا...
Thanks!
شكرًا لكم
I wouldn't have been able to protect the village without you guys!
لم أكن لأحمي القرية لولا وجودكم
What're you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
If it weren't for you, I wouldn't have done a thing!
لم أكن لأتحرك لو أنّك لم تفعل شيئًا
Me neither!
وأنا أيضًا
Who cares about that?
هذا لا يهم
I made a killing!
!فقد حصلت على كنز
Thanks to this incident,
ساعدتني هذه الحادثة على اتخاذ قرار
Captain Usopp! What was it you wanted to talk to us about?
ما الذي أردت التحدث عنه أيها القبطان أوسوب؟
You guys fought well against those Black Cat Pirates!
...أحسنتم بقتال قراصنة القط الأسود أولئك
As captain, I feel very proud!
أنا في غاية الفخر بكم بصفتي قبطانكم
We overcame our biggest and greatest battle since we formed
تغلبنا على أكبر وأعظم معركة منذ أن شكلنا
the Usopp Pirates five years ago, when you guys were just four years old!
!قراصنة أوسوب قبل خمس سنوات حين كنتم بعمر الرابعة فقط
– Yeah!
!أجل
So, I know this is sudden...
،ولذلك، أعلم أنّ هذا مفاجئ
but I've decided to set out to sea by myself!
لكنّي قررت الإبحار وحدي
I'm gonna be a real pirate!
!سأصير قرصانًا حقيقيًّا
I'd always been unsure of whether I should stay or go...
...كنت محتارًا دائمًا ما إن كنت أريد البقاء هنا إلى الأبد أم لا
But... when I met them, I finally made up my mind!
لكن حين رأيتهم، اتخذت قراري أخيرًا
I feel that as a man, I must set out onto the vast ocean!
أشعر أنّه بما أنّي رجل، فعليّ أن أُبحر في هذا البحر الواسع
So...
لذلك، سأغادر هذه القرية
The pirate flag is calling me!
:السبب واحد
What other reason do you need?!
!علم القراصنة يناديني
Captain! You're lying, right?!
ألست تكذب أيها القبطان؟
You're lying again, right?!
أليست هذه كذبة أيضًا؟
It's way too sudden!
من التسرع أن تفعل ذلك
Don't you love this village, Captain?!
ألا تحب هذه القرية أيّها القبطان؟
What'll happen to the Usopp Pirates?!
ماذا سيحلّ بقراصنة أوسوب؟
You've been good to me, guys...
سببتُ لكم كثيرًا من المتاعب
I plan to leave without telling the villagers.
أنوي المغادرة دون إخبار القرويين
Give them my regards.
أبلغوهم تحيّاتي
No...
...لا
I don't want to!
!لا أريد
Don't go, Captain!
!لا تذهب أيّها القبطان
Do you remember this place?
أتذكرون هذا المكان؟
This is where we first met.
إنّه المكان الذي التقينا فيه أول مرة
All done!
!انتهيت
Mr. Liar!
أيّها الأخ الكذاب
Who are you guys?! Don't act all buddy-buddy with me!
من أنتم؟ ما هذا التودّد؟
But you're famous!
لأنّك مشهور
Yeah, you're like a celebrity...
...أجل، إنّك مشهور
I see!
!فهمت
Finally some respect! So, people are now calling me Captain Usopp!
بدأ الناس بمناداتي القبطان أوسوب بكل احترام إذًا
Everyone calls you Usopp the Liar!
يناديك الجميع بالكذاب أوسوب
Alright! From this day forth, you're members of the Usopp Pirates too!
!حسنٌ، أنتم أعضاء في طاقم قراصنة أوسوب بدءًا من اليوم
– What?
ماذا؟
Don't "what" me!
!لا تقولوا هذا
A lot's happened, huh?
ألم يحدث الكثير؟
It's Cerberus!
!سيربيروس! طاردوه
A dragon!
!تنين! اقبضوا عليه
Flour Star!
!نجمة الدقيق
You're amazing, Captain!
إنّك مذهل يا قبطان
But of course!
!بالطبع! فأنا محارب بحر شجاع
We don't wanna hear about the good old days!
لا نريد سماع هذه الذكريات
Yeah! We don't wanna hear about that!
!صحيح، لا نريد سماعها
This isn't like you, Captain!
!هذا ليس من شيمك أيّها القبطان
Why are you saying this stuff now?!
لماذا تقول هذه الأشياء الآن؟
It's almost like you're...
...وكأنّك
You're so stupid, Captain!
!إنّك أحمق أيّها القبطان
Stupid!
!أحمق
What are your ambitions in life?!
ما طموحكم؟
To run a pub!
أن أدير حانة
To be a master carpenter!
أن أصبح نجّارًا محترفًا
To be a novelist!
أن أصبح كاتب روايات
Then swear right here that you'll continue on each of your paths...
إ-إذًا أقسموا هنا أنّكم ستستمرون بدروبكم جميعًا
and never let the fires of your ambitions go out!
!وأنّكم لن تسمحوا لنيران طموحاتكم أن تخمد
As of today...
...اعتبارًا من اليوم
the Usopp Pirates...
...فإنّ مجموعة قراصنة أوسوب
are disbanded!
!حُلّت
Well, we've eaten. We should get going now.
تناولنا الطعام، علينا الذهاب الآن
Yeah...
معك حق
There you are!
كنتم هنا إذًا
Hey, miss!
أهلًا يا آنسة
You're out of bed already?
أبوسعك النهوض من فراشك؟
Yes...
أجل
My illness this past year was due to the grief from losing my parents.
مرضي خلال السنة الماضية
Usopp's been there to cheer me up, but...
وأبهجني أوسوب-سان كثيرًا أيضًا
I can't stay coddled forever!
لا ينبغي لي أن أُدلّل طوال الوقت
I've prepared a little something for you as a token of my gratitude!
أعددت هدية لكم جميعًا أهديها لكم من أعماق قلبي
Please accept it!
أرجوكم اقبلوها
All packed...
انتهيت من حزم أغراضي
Guess it's farewell to this house, too!
إنّه الوداع لهذا المنزل أيضًا
What?!
ماذا؟
What the...? I can't get out!
يا لهذه المصيبة... لا أستطيع الخروج
Damn it!
!سحقًا
A caravel!
!كارفيل
Can we really have this?!
أيمكننا الحصول عليها حقًّا؟
Yes, it's all yours!
أجل، استخدموها رجاءً
It's a slightly older model, but I designed it myself!
إنّها قديمة قليلًا ولكنّي صممتها بنفسي
A carvel-built caravel, with lateen sails and a central stern rudder...
سفينة شراعيّة مصنوعة على طريقة كارفيل
the Going Merry!
!إنها غوينغ ميري
Let me explain the running rigging!
دعني أشرح لك طريقة عمل حبال الأشرعة
First, about the clew-garnet yard adjustment–
...أوّلًا، بشأن ضبط ياردات شبكة كروغر
No, no!
!لا، لا! اشرح السفينة لي
What a nice ship!
يا لروعتها من سفينة
Especially the front—it's so cool!
!لاسيّما مقدمتها، إنّها رائعة
We've loaded it with everything we thought you might need on your voyage.
ملأناها بكلّ شيء قد تحتاجونه في رحلتكم
Thanks! It leaves everything to be desired!
!شكرًا لك، إنّها مثلى
It's "nothing to be desired," you idiot.
.بل عليك أن تقول «مثاليّة» أيّها الغبي
Stop this thing!
أوقفوا هذا الشيء
Usopp!
!أوسوب-سان
What's he doing?
ماذا يفعل؟
Let's just stop him.
لنوقفه على أيّ حال
He's about to collide with the ship.
سيصطدم مباشرة بالسفينة على هذا الحال
Th-Thanks...
...شـ-شكرًا لكما
Yeah.
لا بأس
So... you're really going out to sea, Usopp?
.ستخوض غمار البحر حقًّا إذًا يا أوسوب-سان
Yeah.
أجل، قررت أن أذهب قبل أن أبدأ بتغيير رأيي
Don't stop me now.
لا توقفيني
I won't.
لن أفعل
I could just tell somehow.
توقعت ذلك
That's kind of sad, too!
لكن هذا يحزنني قليلًا
The next time I come to this village,
،حين أزور هذه القرية في المرة القادمة
my stories will sound more unbelievable than any tall tale!
فسأخبرك عن قصص مغامرات تبدو كالكذب أكثر من الكذب نفسه
Okay! I look forward to it!
!أجل، أتطلع لها
You guys take care, too!
!وأنتم اعتنوا بأنفسكم! فلنلتق في مكانٍ ثانيةً
How come?
لماذا؟
Huh? "How come?"
ماذا؟ لماذا؟
Man, would it kill you to play nice?
...إنّك غير اجتماعي حقًّا
I'm gonna be a pirate too, so we'll meet on the high seas eventually!
!سأصير قرصانًا مثلكم، لذا سنتقابل في البحر يومًا
What're you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
Get on already.
اركب بسرعة
You're one of us now, aren't you?
ألسنا رفاقًا الآن؟
I-I...
...ا-القبطان
I get to be captain, right?!
ألستُ أنا القبطان؟
Don't be dumb!
!لا تتحامق، أنا القبطان
There goes the captain...
...ذهب القبطان
Yeah.
أجل
But he's with those guys, so I feel less worried now.
ولكن بما أنّه معهم فقد ارتحت قليلًا
Yeah.
صحيح. لم أرَ أقوياء مثلهم
It makes sense though.
ما باليد حيلة
He always said he wanted to be a pirate.
طالما كان يقول إنّه يريد أن يصبح قرصانًا
The villagers won't be happy to hear it, though...
سيحزن القرويون حين نخبرهم عن هذا
It's all so sudden... He's the reason this place was so lively.
هذا مفاجئ، لقد كان يُبهج الأجواء وحده
I just had an idea!
!لديّ فكرة
– What is it?
ماذا؟
Merry...
...ميري
Yes?
نعم؟
Lying is painful...
...الكذب يؤلم
Are you referring to Klahadore?
أتعنين كلاهادور؟
No...
...لا
You mean how you actually wanted to stop Usopp from going?
أتعنين كيف أنّك أردتِ منع أوسوب-كن من الذهاب حقًّا؟
Miss...
يا آنستي، أخبرني القرويون قصة عن طفولته ذات مرة
Shortly after Usopp's father ran off from the village,
،بعد وقت قصير من مغادرة والد أوسوب لهذه القرية
his mother passed away.
.فقد والدته
The pirates are coming!
!أتى القراصنة
Dad's pirate ship is here!
!قراصنة أبي هنا
H-Hold on, Usopp!
!تـ-توقف يا أوسوب! لا ينبغي لك أن تصرخ
Dad came to pick us up!
عاد أبي لنا
D-Don't be silly... Usopp...
...لـ-لا تكن سخيفًا يا أوسوب
But he said he'd take us with him when you get better, Mom!
!ولكنّه قال إنّه سيأخذنا معه للمغامرة حين تتحسنين يا أمّي
Your father won't be coming back...
...لن يعود والدك
But... I'm proud to have married him...
ولكنّي فخورة لتزوّجي منه
There's a miracle cure out there!
!هناك دواء أسطوري يمكنه شفاء أيّ مرض
You're so silly...
...يا لسخافتك... إنك تحلم كثيرًا
I don't care if I'm silly!
!لا بأس بكوني سخيفًا، أنا أحلم فعلًا
I'm the son of a pirate!
!وأنا ابن قرصان
Grow up to be a brave man like your father...
...اكبر لتصير رجلًا شجاعًا مثل والدك
The pirates are coming!
!أتى القراصنة
Perhaps out of loneliness,
،ربّما بسبب وحدته
he continued to shout it out after she passed.
استمر بتلك الصرخات بعد وفاة والدته
All in the hopes that his father's pirate ship would one day be at the shore...
،آملًا أن تأتي سفينة قراصنة والده يومًا إلى الساحل
that one day, he would come back for him.
آملًا أن يأتي له يومًا
The villagers say that lie of his also contains his wish.
يقول القرويون إنّ كذبته تلك تحمل أمنية أيضًا
Pirates!
!قراصنة
As someone who lost his own parents in this village,
،بصفته فتًى خسر والديه في هذه القرية
it's no wonder he couldn't ignore you when you lost yours.
فإنّه لم يتمكن من تركك وحيدة بما أنّه حدث نفس الشيء لك
You will need to grow stronger now, too!
عليكِ أن تصيري أقوى
To live up to everything he's done until today!
استجابةً لكلّ ما فعله حتّى اليوم
Yes!
!أجل
To our new ship and crewmate!
،بمناسبة السفينة الجديدة ورفيقنا الجديد
– Cheers!
!نخبكم
They said they weren't gonna die, that they would fight to live.
قالوا إنّهم يقاتلون للعيش وليس للموت
Usopp's lies always spoke about the joy of living.
طالما كانت تتحدث أكاذيب أوسوب عن متعة العيش
They cheered me up and told me to live!
كانت تبهجني وتخبرني أن أعيش
Indeed.
معكِ حق
Here we go!
!لننطلق
Are we really gonna do this?!
أسنفعلها حقًّا؟
You bet! We're following in our captain's footsteps!
!سنفعلها، سنسير على أثر القبطان
– The pirates are comiiing!
!أتى القراصنة
You know what, Merry?
أوَتعلم يا ميري؟
I'm going to be a doctor!
!سأصير طبيبة
What a wonderful ambition!
!يا لعظمته من هدف